Guide to the Duke University Progress Pictures Collection, 1925-1932
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- East Campus
  - 19260615EC0131.jpg (Image 115)
    - Center of site looking north showing scaffolding and masonry on Library and Alspaugh house
    - Library, East
  - 19260615EC0132.jpg (Image 116)
    - 1926-06-15
    - North end of site looking west from roof of Bassett, showing Pegram House and foundation of Auditorium
    - Pegram
  - 19260701EC0141.jpg (Image 117)
    - 1926-07-01
    - North end of site looking east showing Bassett and Brown Houses, foundation of Auditorium
    - Campus View
  - 19260701EC0142.jpg (Image 118)
    - 1926-07-01
    - North end of Pegram Hall, probably
    - Pegram
  - *19260701EC0433.jpg (Image 119)
    - 1926-07-01
    - Center of site looking northwest showing Library, Alspaugh and Pegram
    - Campus View
    - [Photo is numbered 133]
  - *19260701EC0434.jpg (Image 120)
    - 1926-07-01
    - Center of site looking southwest showing scaffolding and masonry on Library
    - Library, East
    - [Photo is numbered 134]
  - *19260701EC0435.jpg (Image 121)
    - 1926-07-01
    - Bassett House and foundation of Auditorium, north center of site looking east
    - Bassett
    - [Photo is numbered 135]
  - *19260701EC0436.jpg (Image 122)
    - 1926-07-01
    - Foundation of Auditorium, looking northeast
    - Baldwin Auditorium
    - [Photo is numbered 136]
  - *19260701EC0439.jpg (Image 123)
    - 1926-07-01
    - Center of site looking southeast showing foundation of Science Building
    - Science
    - [Photo is numbered 139]
  - *19260701EC0440.jpg (Image 124)
    - 1926-07-01
    - Center of site looking north showing Library and Alspaugh (low angle shot)
    - Library, East
    - [Photo is numbered 140]
  - 19260715EC0143.jpg (Image 125)
    - 1926-07-15
    - Library
    - Library, East
  - 19260715EC0144.jpg (Image 126)
    - 1926-07-15
    - Center of site looking west showing Library scaffolding
    - Library, East
    - 143
  - 19260715EC0145.jpg (Image 127)
    - 1926-07-15
    - Pegram House and foundation of Auditorium, north center of site looking west
    - Bassett
    - 144
  - 19260715EC0146.jpg (Image 128)
    - 1926-07-15
    - Foundation of Auditorium, looking northeast
    - Baldwin Auditorium
  - 19260715EC0148.jpg (Image 129)
    - 1926-07-15
    - Center of site looking northeast showing railcars, masonry work on Union, Bassett and Brown
    - Campus View
  - 19260715EC0149.jpg (Image 130)
    - 1926-07-15
    - Center of site looking southeast showing scaffolding of Science Building; Aycock in background
    - Science
  - 19260715EC0150.jpg (Image 131)
    - 1926-07-15
    - North end of Carr Building
    - Carr
  - 19260715EC0151.jpg (Image 132)
    - 1926-07-15
    - Center of site looking northwest showing Library and Alspaugh
    - Campus View
  - 19260715EC0152.jpg (Image 133)
    - 1926-07-15
    - Front of Union Building looking north showing end of Brown House
    - Union, East
  - 19260801EC0153.jpg (Image 134)
    - 1926-08-01
    - East side of site looking northwest showing corner of old Library, new Library, Alspaugh and Pegram
    - Dormitories
  - 19260801EC0154.jpg (Image 135)
    - 1926-08-01
    - Pegram House and foundation of Auditorium, north center of site looking west; railroad cars
    - Pegram
  - 19260801EC0155.jpg (Image 136)
    - 1926-08-01
    - Center of site looking northeast showing workers at site of old Alspaugh dormitory; Union Building in background. Not an original print.
    - Campus View
  - 19260801EC0156.jpg (Image 137)
    - 1926-08-01
    - Center of site looking northeast showing Brown House, railcar and Building supplies
  - 19260801EC0157.jpg (Image 138)
    - 1926-08-01
    - North side of Carr Building; workman walking along railroad track
  - 19260801EC0159.jpg (Image 139)
    - 1926-08-01
    - Foundations of Science Building; Aycock in background
  - 19260801EC0162.jpg (Image 140)
    - 1926-08-01
    - Foundations and framing of Auditorium, looking northeast
  - 19260816EC0163.jpg (Image 141)
    - 1926-08-16
    - Pegram House and foundation of Auditorium, north center of site looking west; railroad cars
  - 19260816EC0164.jpg (Image 142)
    - 1926-08-16
    - Foundations of Science Building; Aycock in background
  - 19260816EC0165.jpg (Image 143)
    - 1926-08-16
    - Excavation for Faculty apartments (now Wilson House)
  - 19260816EC0166.jpg (Image 144)
    - 1926-08-16
    - Bassett House and foundation of Auditorium, north center of site looking east.
  - 19260816EC0169.jpg (Image 145)
    - 1926-08-16
    - Center of site looking north showing Library and Alspaugh
    - Library, East
    - "Library" engraving on pediment is visible
  - 19260816EC0170.jpg (Image 146)
    - 1926-08-16
    - Center of site looking northwest showing Bassett and Brown houses, railroad cars, Building supplies
    - Campus View
  - 19260816EC0171.jpg (Image 147)
    - 1926-08-16
    - Excavation for Faculty apartments (now Wilson House), Union Building, Brown House
    - Campus View
  - 19260816EC0172.jpg (Image 148)
    - 1926-08-16
    - North side of Carr Building
    - Carr
  - 19260901EC0173.jpg (Image 149)
    - 1926-09-01
    - North side of Carr Building
    - Carr
  - 19260901EC0174.jpg (Image 150)
    - 1926-09-01
    - Foundation of Baldwin Auditorium, looking northeast
    - Baldwin Auditorium
  - 19260901EC0175.jpg (Image 151)
    - 1926-09-01
    - Union Building showing scaffolding, Brown and Bassett Houses in background
    - Union, East
  - 19260901EC0176.jpg (Image 152)
    - 1926-09-01
    - Baldwin Auditorium steelwork, Bassett and Brown Houses in background; looking southeast
    - Baldwin Auditorium
  - 19260901EC0177.jpg (Image 153)
    - 1926-09-01
    - Baldwin Auditorium steelwork, Pegram and Alspaugh Houses in background; looking southwest
    - Baldwin Auditorium
  - 19260901EC0178.jpg (Image 154)
    - 1926-09-01
    - Library looking southeast
    - Library, East
  - 19260901EC0179.jpg (Image 155)
    - 1926-09-01
    - Front of Union Building looking north showing end of Brown House
    - Union, East
  - 19260901EC0180.jpg (Image 156)
    - 1926-09-01
    - Foundations for Faculty Apartments and Science Building; Aycock in background, Craven Memorial at right
    - Campus View
  - 19260901EC0181.jpg (Image 157)
    - 1926-09-01
    - Library, Alspaugh and Pegram from center of site looking northwest
    - Campus View
  - 19260901EC0182.jpg (Image 158)
    - 1926-09-01
    - Front of Library showing scaffolding and columns, south end of Alspaugh
    - Library, East
  - 19260915EC0187.jpg (Image 159)
    - 1926-09-15
    - Foundation and steelwork on Baldwin Auditorium, looking northeast; Bassett House at right
    - Baldwin Auditorium
  - 19260915EC0188.jpg (Image 160)
    - 1926-09-15
    - Foundation and steelwork on Baldwin Auditorium, looking southeast; Bassett House at right
    - Baldwin Auditorium
  - 19260915EC0189.jpg (Image 161)
    - 1926-09-15
    - North side of Carr Building
    - Carr
  - 19260915EC0190.jpg (Image 162)
    - 1926-09-15
    - Alspaugh and Pegram Houses from floor of Auditorium, Library roof visible in background, south
    - Dormitories
  - 19260915EC0191.jpg (Image 163)
    - 1926-09-15
    - View south from top of Union Building, showing foundations for Faculty Apartments and Science Building
    - Campus View
  - 19260915EC0192.jpg (Image 164)
    - 1926-09-15
    - East Union Building, with Bassett House and steelwork for Baldwin Auditorium in background
    - Union, East
- West Campus
  - 19270412WC0001.jpg (Image 165)
    - 1927-04-12
    - View taken from center of Quadrangle looking along Quadrangle with location of Medical School in background
    - Medicine
    - Note: West photos 1-5 are described on the verso; these descriptions do not resume until 41
  - 19270412WC0002.jpg (Image 166)
    - 1927-04-12
    - View taken from center of Quadrangle looking along Quadrangle showing proposed location of dormitories in center of picture
    - Residential
  - 19270412WC0003.jpg (Image 167)
    - 1927-04-12
    - View taken from center of Quadrangle looking across same with proposed location of Chapel at the upper center of picture. This shows fill being made between Union Building and library.
    - Chapel
    - Looking toward chapel site
  - 19270412WC0004.jpg (Image 168)
    - 1927-04-12
    - View taken from proposed location of Chapel looking towards fountain showing the grading near center of Quadrangle
    - Campus View
    - Looking toward traffic circle
  - 19270412WC0005.jpg (Image 169)
    - 1927-04-12
    - View taken from center of Quadrangle looking towards proposed location of fountain. This shows clearing for the Building of large fill for main entrance to University.
    - Campus View
    - Looking toward traffic circle from center of Quad
  - 19270609WC0006.jpg (Image 170)
    - 1927-06-09
    - View looking toward chapel site [supplied by Archives]
    - Chapel
    - Looking toward chapel site
  - 19270609WC0007.jpg (Image 171)
    - 1927-06-09
    - View looking towards site of Medical School, hole curve in railroad track [supplied by Archives]
    - Academic
    - Looking towards site of med school hole curve in RR track
  - 19270609WC0008.jpg (Image 172)
    - 1927-06-09
    - View looking to dorm site [supplied by Archives]
    - Residential
    - Looking to dorm site
  - 19270609WC0009.jpg (Image 173)
    - 1927-06-09
    - Perhaps land to the east of the construction plateau [supplied by Archives]
    - Campus View
    - Perhaps land to the east of the construction plateau
  - 19270609WC0010.jpg (Image 174)
    - 1927-06-09
    - View from chapel site toward traffic circle [supplied by Archives]
    - Campus View
    - From chapel site toward traffic circle?
  - 19270609WC0011.jpg (Image 175)
    - 1927-06-09
    - View
    - Campus View
    - Plateau showing early excavations?
  - 19270708WC0012.jpg (Image 176)
    - 1927-07-08
    - Site of Library?
    - Library
    - Site of Library; chapel site to the left
  - 19270708WC0013.jpg (Image 177)
    - 1927-07-08
    - Site of academic quad showing railroad track; Medical School site is at center?
    - Academic
    - Academic quad
  - 19270708WC0014.jpg (Image 178)
    - 1927-07-08
    - Site of future causeway looking east; site of future gardens ot the left?
    - Campus View
    - Possibly along causeway looking to traffic circle
  - 19270708WC0015.jpg (Image 179)
    - 1927-07-08
    - Site of residential quads looking south along railroad track? Several workers' faces are visible
    - Residential
    - people
  - 19270708WC0016.jpg (Image 180)
    - 1927-07-08
    - Valley north of future causeway looking east? Site of future gardens at left; steamshovel visible
    - Campus View
    - land off the plateau
  - 19270708WC0017.jpg (Image 181)
    - 1927-07-08
    - Excavations in residential quad?
    - Campus View
    - Plateau showing early excavations?
  - 19270804WC0018.jpg (Image 182)
    - 1927-08-04
    - Excavations for utilities in residential quad?
    - Campus View
    - Plateau showing early excavations?
  - 19270804WC0019.jpg (Image 183)
    - 1927-08-04
    - Excavations for utilities, main quad? Workers' faces visible; "The Duke Endowment" steamshovel No. 1
    - Campus View
    - people, TDE steamshovel
  - 19270804WC0020.jpg (Image 184)
    - 1927-08-04
    - Excavations in residential quad?
    - Campus View
    - Plateau showing early excavations?
  - 19270804WC0021.jpg (Image 185)
    - 1927-08-04
    - View along future causeway looking west towards main quad?
    - Campus View
    - ?
  - 19270804WC0022.jpg (Image 186)
    - 1927-08-04
    - Excavations in residential quad?
    - Campus View
    - Possibly the site of the dorms, from the south
  - 19270804WC0023.jpg (Image 187)
    - 1927-08-04
    - Excavations for utilities, main quad?
    - Campus View
    - a trench somewhere
  - 19270808WC0024.jpg (Image 188)
    - 1927-08-08
    - Quarry?
    - Quarry
  - 19270808WC0025.jpg (Image 189)
    - 1927-08-08
    - Quarry?
    - Quarry
    - ?
  - 19270908WC0026.jpg (Image 190)
    - 1927-09-08
    - Excavation for hospital and medical school Buildings, viewed from the north?
    - Campus View
    - possibly an area near the quarry
  - 19270908WC0027.jpg (Image 191)
    - 1927-09-08
    - Quarry?
    - Quarry
  - 19270908WC0028.jpg (Image 192)
    - 1927-09-08
    - Excavation for hospital and medical school Buildings?
    - Campus View
    - quarry?
  - 19270908WC0029.jpg (Image 193)
    - 1927-09-08
    - Site of academic quad showing railroad track; site of medical school is at center
    - Academic
  - 19270908WC0030.jpg (Image 194)
    - 1927-09-08
    - Excavation; location undetermined
    - Campus View
    - excavation for ?
  - 19270908WC0031.jpg (Image 195)
    - 1927-09-08
    - Quarry?
    - Quarry
    - ?
  - 19270908WC0032.jpg (Image 196)
    - 1927-09-08
    - View east along future causeway, with portions of future Circuit Drive roughed in
    - Campus View
    - towards traffic circle
  - 19271114WC0035.jpg (Image 197)
    - 1927-11-14
    - View towards main quad from site of Craven Quadrangle showing excavation and forms for dormitory?
    - Craven - A
    - foundation
  - 19271114WC0036.jpg (Image 198)
    - 1927-11-14
    - Excavation for Craven Quadrangle, looking south?
    - Craven - A
  - 19271129WC0037.jpg (Image 199)
    - 1927-11-29
    - Site of residential Quadrangles looking northwest?
    - Craven - A
    - ?
  - 19271129WC0038.jpg (Image 200)
    - 1927-11-29
    - Site of residential Quadrangles looking southwest?
    - Craven - A
    - ?
  - 19271129WC0039.jpg (Image 201)
    - 1927-11-29
    - Excavation for hospital and medical school Buildings?
    - ?
  - 19271129WC0040.jpg (Image 202)
    - 1927-11-29
    - Excavation for hospital and medical school Buildings?
    - ?
  - 19280103WC0041.jpg (Image 203)
    - 1928-01-03
    - Picture taken from near Union Building, looking along front of Dormitories. This shows the concrete foundation fninished up to grade of main Quadrangle.
    - Residential
  - 19280103WC0042.jpg (Image 204)
    - 1928-01-03
    - Picture taken from near service entrance, looking towards main entrance of Hospital, which entrance is located where mixer now stands. This shows concrete wall around sub-basement.
    - Hospital
  - 19280103WC0043.jpg (Image 205)
    - 1928-01-03
    - Picture taken from near entrance of Group "C" Dormitory looking towards Union Building. This shows the front wall of Group "C" dormitory built up to Quadrangle grade, also forms built for concrete foundation of Union Building. A large pile of stone is located between Union Building and Library.
    - Union
  - 19280103WC0044.jpg (Image 206)
    - 1928-01-03
    - Taken from Quadrangle in front of Chapel, looking across Union Building, with Group "C" Dormitory in the background. This shows mixing plant and forms for Union Building.
    - Union
  - 19280103WC0045.jpg (Image 207)
    - 1928-01-03
    - Taken from near the center of Medical School, looking across the hospital. This shows part of the service tunnel under basement floor. Mixer is located at the main entrance to hospital.
    - Hospital
  - 19280103WC0046.jpg (Image 208)
    - 1928-01-03
    - Taken from service court at far end of Group "C" dormitories. This looking across Group "C" Dormitories and Union Building, and shows forms on right of picture ready for pouring first floor of Group "C" Dormitories. The location of the Hospital and Medical School is shown in the upper center of the picture.
    - Kilgo - C
  - 19280202WC0047.jpg (Image 209)
    - 1928-02-02
    - Taken from end of Group "C" Dormitories looking across Union Building toward location for School of Religion
    - Union
  - 19280202WC0048.jpg (Image 210)
    - 1928-02-02
    - Showing close-up detail of the Hospital near the Service Entrance. This shows sub-basement of Hospital.
    - Hospital
    - people
  - 19280202WC0049.jpg (Image 211)
    - 1928-02-02
    - Union Buliding in foreground with Group "C" Dormitories in the background.
    - Kilgo - C
  - 19280202WC0050.jpg (Image 212)
    - 1928-02-02
    - Group "C" Dormitories. Taken near Union Building looking across Group "C" Dormitories.
    - Kilgo - C
  - 19280202WC0051.jpg (Image 213)
    - 1928-02-02
    - Taken from entrance to Medical School looking across Hospital
    - Hospital
  - 19280202WC0052.jpg (Image 214)
    - 1928-02-02
    - Taken from extreme rear end looking across Group "C" Dormitories Union Building, with Hospital and Medical School in background.
    - Medicine
  - 19280305WC0053.jpg (Image 215)
    - 1928-03-05
    - View showing stonework laid on rear of Group "C" Dormitories. This shows stonework at the highest approximate level with first floor.
    - Kilgo - C
    - Good close-up of stone wall
  - 19280305WC0054.jpg (Image 216)
    - 1928-03-05
    - View taken from Medical School looking across Hospital, showing all foundations placed ready for steelwork, and practically all backfilling completed around concrete. Also showing railroad track laid through the center of the Hospital.
    - Hospital
  - 19280305WC0055.jpg (Image 217)
    - 1928-03-05
    - View showing part of foundation for Hospital near Service Entrance. Extreme lower left shows sub-basement.
    - Hospital
  - 19280305WC0056.jpg (Image 218)
    - 1928-03-05
    - View taken from end of group "C" Dormitories, looking across Union Building. This shows outside walls of Union Building and foundation of basement floor level.
    - Union
  - 19280305WC0057.jpg (Image 219)
    - 1928-03-05
    - View taken from service court back of Group "C" Dormitories, showing first floor of Group "C" Dormitories with steel columns erected along corridors.
    - Kilgo - C
  - 19280305WC0058.jpg (Image 220)
    - 1928-03-05
    - View taken from rear of Union Building, looking across same toward Group "C" Dormitories. This shows forms being constructed for the basement floor. The concrete shown in the center of the picture is up to the elevation of the basement floor.
    - Kilgo - C
  - 19280403WC0059.jpg (Image 221)
    - 1928-04-03
    - View looking across the foundation for Hospital and Medical School. Shows derrick being set up for erecting steel structure.
    - Hospital
  - 19280403WC0060.jpg (Image 222)
    - 1928-04-03
    - Taken from court in front of Chapel looking across Union Building foundation. This shows Union Building concrete completed to basement floor. In the background is shown Group "C" Dormitory with window frames set to first floor.
    - Union
  - 19280405WC0061.jpg (Image 223)
    - 1928-04-05
    - View taken from approximate location of Group "B" Dormitory, looking toward the rear of Group "C" Dormitory, showing structural steel and stonework.
    - Kilgo - C
  - 19280405WC0062.jpg (Image 224)
    - 1928-04-05
    - View taken from main Quadrangle at entrance of Medical School looking across Medical School and Hospital foundation.
    - Medicine
  - 19280405WC0063.jpg (Image 225)
    - 1928-04-05
    - View taken from main Quadrangle between Union Building and Group "C" Dormitory, looking across Union Building, showing concrete basement floor complete, and on right, forms being erected for first floor of the Union Building. In center of picture is shown excavation for classroom and Auditorium. In upper center is shown location for Chapel.
    - Union
  - 19280405WC0064.jpg (Image 226)
    - 1928-04-05
    - Taken from end of Building showing a closeup detail of Group "C" Dormitory where same connect to Union Building.
    - Kilgo - C
  - 19280501WC0065.jpg (Image 227)
    - 1928-05-01
    - View taken from the rear of service court of Group "C" Dormitories showing stonework and steel erected.
    - Kilgo - C
  - 19280501WC0066.jpg (Image 228)
    - 1928-05-01
    - View taken from end of Medical School looking across Hospital showing steel erected up to second floor level on the Hospital end of the Building.
    - Hospital
  - 19280501WC0067.jpg (Image 229)
    - 1928-05-01
    - View showing the front of Group "C" Dormitories adjoining the Union Building.
    - Kilgo - C
  - 19280501WC0068.jpg (Image 230)
    - 1928-05-01
    - View looking across basement floor of Union Building showing Group "C" Dormitories in the background.
    - Kilgo - C
  - 19280501WC0069.jpg (Image 231)
    - 1928-05-01
    - View of Hospital taken from service court showing steel erected from sub-basement floor to second floor.
    - Hospital
  - 19280501WC0070.jpg (Image 232)
    - 1928-05-01
    - View taken from end of Group "C" Dormitories looking across Union Building, showing forms being erected above basement floor.
    - Union
  - 19280530WC0071.jpg (Image 233)
    - 1928-05-30
    - View looking at the rear of Group "C" Dormitories showing stonework completed to third floor level.
    - Kilgo - C
  - 19280530WC0072.jpg (Image 234)
    - 1928-05-30
    - View showing the front of Group "C" Dormitories near location of Group "B" Dormitories. This shows stonework on the front of the Building built up to the third floor level. [Dated 1928-05-31 on photo]
    - Kilgo - C
  - 19280530WC0073.jpg (Image 235)
    - 1928-05-30
    - View showing the entrance court to Hospital, showing structural steel erected on this part of the Building to fourth floor. [Dated 1928-05-31 on back of photo]
    - Hospital
  - 19280530WC0074.jpg (Image 236)
    - 1928-05-30
    - View taken from end of Medical School looking across Medical School and Hospital, showing steel partly erected to fourth floor on Hospital end of Building. [Dated 1928-05-31 on back of photo]
    - Hospital
  - 19280530WC0075.jpg (Image 237)
    - 1928-05-30
    - View of Heating Plant showing foundations for Building coal trestle and stack. [Dated 1928-05-31 on back of photo]
    - Heating plant
  - 19280530WC0076.jpg (Image 238)
    - 1928-05-30
    - View taken from front of Library looking across same, with foundation for School of Religion at right of picture. [Dated 1928-05-31 on back of photo]
    - Library
    - Note: many pictures show both the Law and the Library Buildings
  - 19280530WC0077.jpg (Image 239)
    - 1928-05-30
    - View taken from Quadrangle near the front of classroom and Auditorium, showing Union Building below first floor, with Group "C" Dormitories in upper right hand part of picture. [Dated 1928-05-31 on back of photo]
    - Union
  - 19280530WC0078.jpg (Image 240)
    - 1928-05-30
    - Taken from near the rear of Union Building. Showing Union Building on the left and end of Group "C" Dormitories on right. [Dated 1928-05-31 on back of photo]
    - Union
  - 19280618WC0079.jpg (Image 241)
    - 1928-06-18
    - View of the Quarry near Hillsborough showing method of operation.
    - Quarry
  - 19280618WC0080.jpg (Image 242)
    - 1928-06-18
    - View of the Quarry near Hillsborough showing close up view of rock face.
    - Quarry
  - 19280618WC0081.jpg (Image 243)
    - 1928-06-18
    - View of the Quarry near Hillsborough showing rock before same is loosened with dynamite.
    - Quarry
  - 19280618WC0082.jpg (Image 244)
    - 1928-06-18
    - View of the Quarry near Hillsborough showing rock being loaded on cars. Also on the right of the picture is shown waste material from Quarry.
    - Quarry
  - 19280702WC0089.jpg (Image 245)
    - 1928-07-02
    - Showing service court entrance at Hospital. All of steel has been erected to fourth floor, and roof steel completed on wing of Building.
    - Hospital
  - 19280702WC0090.jpg (Image 246)
    - 1928-07-02
    - View showing steel on Hospital part of Building erected to Fourth Floor. No steel has been set on Medical School.
    - Hospital
  - 19280702WC0091.jpg (Image 247)
    - 1928-07-02
    - Group "C" Dormitories showing entrance to court from large Quadrangle.
    - Kilgo - C
  - 19280702WC0092.jpg (Image 248)